

# Miss Ilaria Giovanelli Clinical Psychologist, Educational Psychologist, CBT, Children, neuropsychology, etc.

Health City, Davenport House, 16 Pepper Street, Canary Wharf, London E14 9RP. Tel: 0333 800 3006, 0333 789 0012. Email: <a href="mailto:info@healthcity.org.uk">info@healthcity.org.uk</a>, Ilaria.Giovanelli@healthcity.org.uk



### **Personal Profile**

My expertise is clinical neuropsychology. I have worked with a lot of different pathological conditions both in adults, older adults and children. I know several test for cognitive assessment and how to design a rehabilitation project.



#### Key skills and attributes

- · Clinical psychology.
- · Educational psychology.
- Cognitive behavioural therapy.
- Neuropsychology, neuropsychological assessment and cognitive assessment.
- Adults, older adults and children clinical psychology.
- Learning difficulties, ADHD, autism, and special needs.
- Range of mental health conditions, example, anxiety, depression and PTSD following a car accident.
- Great knowledge in selection-administration-scoring -Interpretation of instruments.
- Able to utilise multi-model interventions.
- Able to work in a multidisciplinary team and in an international context.
- · Multi lingual in English, Italian and Spanish



#### Education

6 July 2021. Registered to HCPC as Educational and Clinical psychologist number PYL039660 5 December 2019. Member of the British Psychologist Society number 506100 and GBC

May 2019-June 2019. Intensive course (200H) in HR management, Challenge Network, Rome

February 2017-March 2018 . Postgraduate course in Neuropsychology and Clinical Neuroscience of Behaviour, LUMSA University Rome

March 2012. Admitted to the register of psychologists Liguria number 2155.

March 2010. Master's degree in psychology (final mark 109/110), University of Genoa. Dissertation: "Attention in dyslexia: evaluation and treatments)

September 2008 to June 2009. Exchange program at Brookes University, Oxford.

November 2007. Bachelor's degree in psychology of development, (Final Mark 110 cum laude /110), University of Genoa. Dissertation: "Cognitive processes in multiplication (normal development and learning disorders).



#### **Employment Record**

In the latest years I worked in hospitals, public and private clinics, research centres and daily centres. I have good knowledge about diagnosis of different neurological diseases and I own my battery of neuropsychology tests. I have also experience in working with children as I worked a couple of years in summer camps, holiday villages, language schools and as psychologist assistant for students with learning difficulties, ADHD, autism, and special needs.

Here the list the place where I have worked previously.



## Neuropsychology and clinical psychology experiences with adults

May 2023-> June 2023. Locum Clinical psychologist at Teladoc. Delivery of single session consultations for adults, Mental Health Consultations. Provided comprehensive and integrative case formulations, including detailed risk assessments of patients across the lifespan. Provided effective phone-delivered psychotherapy and culturally sensitive interventions and demonstrating awareness of affirming therapeutic work with gender and sexually diverse communities.

November 2022 → Clinical Psychologist Trw Therapy, Northern Lincolnshire and Goole NHS.

Therapy for patients with chronic health and oncology conditions. Facilitating the development of programs and pathways to deliver consultations, assessments, and interventions for individuals following a cancer diagnosis or a chronic health condition. Use of CBT, ACT, CFT techniques. Writing discharge reports, completing triages and risk assessments. Supervisor of assistants.

<u>April 2022-> Clinical psychologist, expert witnesses for Medi spec LDT.</u> Assessment to clients for a professional opinion on how they believe the court should proceed in sentencing with regards to their cognitive functions, mental health such as anxiety, depression and PTSD following a car accident.

January 2021 → November 2022. Assistant psychologist in the Department of Medical psychology, Northern Lincolnshire and Goole NHS. Therapy online for patients with different neurological conditions. Intervention focused on cognitive impairment, low mood and anxiety. Clinical intervention using different models such as CBT,ACT,CFT and discharge of patients using clinical reasoning, knowledge of evidence based practice, investigative and analytical skills. Implementing a range of psychological interventions for individuals, carers, families and groups as appropriate. Interviews with clients, family members and others involved in the client's care. Delivering of online workshops.

<u>August 2019 to December 2019. Walton Centre NHS, Liverpool.</u> Fellowship in general neuroscience. Observation of patients with different kind of neurologic disorders, in particular neurodegenerative diseases and movement disorders. Screening cognitive assessment. I learnt how to manage patients, families and the health care context.

<u>August 2017 to January 2018. Neurogie Bewegt, Berlin.</u> Clinic for Parkinson and others movement disorders, Involvement in a research project including Max Planck institute and others European clinics. Use of neurofeedback for patients with attentional impairments. Supporting recruitment strategies, training in the study protocol, supporting data collection, and data entry. Coordination of the communication about the centres involved in the project.

<u>July 2016 to December 2016. Policlinico Umberto I Roma:</u> Conducting interviews about medical history of patients in order to develop or address differential diagnoses of cognitive impairment, due to Alzheimer's disease, vascular dementia, frontal-temporal lobar degeneration, Parkinson's disease, and other conditions. Cognitive assessment.

October 2015 to April 2016. Fundacion Cien Reina Sofia, Madrid. Research project in Alzheimer's disease and others neurodegenerative disorders. Testing cognitive functions in older volunteers, searching relevant literature about topics in Neuroscience, generating hypothesis from data analysis, scoring and interpreting results, managing databases, disseminating the products of the research. Focus on cognitive reserve and prevention of cognitive impairments.

<u>June 2015 to September 2015.Daily Care center "Il pioppo", Roma.</u> Cognitive stimulation for people with different kind of dementia. Leading groups activities and using techniques as ROT. Support to caregivers and observations of self-helped groups, Development of individual rehabilitation plan according to the needs of the patient

October 2014 to May 2015. Daily care center Manava, Madrid. Leading activities and cognitive sessions for groups with 7 different levels of cognitive impairments from mild to severe. Managing challenging behaviours. Support to the caregivers. Team working with other professionals.

October 2013 to January 2014. Polibea, Madrid. Centre of rehabilitation for brain injury. Supervised training experiences in assessment and cognitive rehabilitation for patients who have survived traumatic brain injuries secondary to motor vehicle accident or who have sustained brain injury due to anoxia, encephalitis, stroke or other neurological conditions. Neuropsychological testing to assess the cognitive impairments.

<u>February 2013 to June 2013. Vitalia, Madrid.</u> Evaluation and rehabilitation of cognitive impairments due to neurodegenerative diseases as Alzheimer, Parkinson and frontotemporal dementia. Conducting groups activities to stimulate cognitive and emotional functions.

October 2010 to March 2011. Centre of Neuropsychology. San Camillo Hospital, Turin. Postgraduate training. Assessments involved a broad-based population including Traumatic Brain Injuries, strokes, Parkinson. Assessments of different neurological conditions with a wide range of instruments (ACE-R, Clock drawing test, Corsi test, Digit Span, Weigle's, Tower of London, FAS, Frontal assessment battery, Rivermead, Rey copy, Trail Making Test, Stroop test, Weschler Scale, BADS, VOSP, Winsconsig, Kohs Block Design test, BIT, Diller).



### Job experiences with children

<u>February 2020 --> Ranstad Education, Liverpool.</u> Teaching assistant for SEN students. Providing essential support to teachers in preschool and school settings, with duties ranging from class preparation to overseeing a child's personal and social development. Helping children with a wide range of severe learning, physical or behavioural difficulties. Assisting children during therapy sessions.

<u>July 2019, Language Team, Leith Academy, Edinburg</u>. Responsible for groups of students. Support both school staff and students during their activities in class and outside. Supervising during the breaks and lunchtime. Managing student behaviour in activities and around the school. Ensuring that the classroom and their rooms were always tidy and in good order. Leading the group in trips during the weekend. Supervising proper behaviour in the college during nights.

October 2018, Ifom Younet, Malta. Tutoring of a school class in Milano participating to the Erasmus project in Malta. Assisting the teacher in the management of students in their placement period. Providing general support and helping with their social development. Preparing and managing the Erasmus documentation such as Learning agreement and Europass. Planning learning activities and trips during the weekend with the teacher.

<u>April to June 2017 Studio Eidon, Rome</u>. Training for the postgraduate course in clinical neuropsychology. Neuropsychological assessment to evaluate the cognitive functions of the children. Administering screening tests in schools in order to identify students with probable learning difficulties

such as Dyslexia, Dyscalculia and Dysgraphia. Understanding the learning process for special need students. Communicating information about the students to schools. Support to the families about understanding the special needs of their children. Completed required documentation on behaviours and interventions. Constant feedback with the schools and teachers.

<u>February 2012 to January 2013. Asociación Valponasca, Madrid.</u> Respond to social and educational needs on daily basis. Assist, direct and promote independence and confidence. Employing a range of learning support techniques to suit individuals. Conducting one to one activity. Helping children in their studies and all areas of the national curriculum. Be aware of school polices. Periodic risk assessment for the students. Supported intellectual and social growth by leading games. Management of challenging behaviour.

<u>September to November 2010 Alassio Centro Salute</u>. Observing neuropsychology testing to make proper diagnosis of different kind of learning difficulties. Treatments and techniques especially for children with Dyslexia and ADHD. Meeting parents and updating them on a child's progress. Constant updating to the schools



#### Languages

Italian: mother tongue English: C1 certificate People Cert Spanish: C1 certificate DELE